Azeez Adeyori Adio

Software Engineer | DevOps Engineer | Cloud Engineer

Ibadan, Oyo State, Nigeria | +234-806-437-4020 | adioadeyoriazeez@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/adeoriazeez

Professional Summary

I'm a Senior Full Stack Developer with 7+ years of experience in tech field, I have used several technologies such as JavaScript, PHP and Python. I led the development of a leaning management, ecommerce and Finance application system, which reduced administrative overhead by 30% and increased monthly active users by 16%. I've also crafted innovative solutions for industries such as fintech, e-commerce, and learning management applications. I continually expand my skill sets to deliver exceptional results.

Skills

DevOps Skills: Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD Pipelines, Jenkins, Git, GitHub, GitLab, Terraform, Terragrunt,

Ansible, Puppet, Chef

Monitoring Tools: Prometheus, Datadog, Grafana

Cloud Platforms: Azure, AWS

Front-End: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React.js and Bootstrap **Back-End:** Node.js, Express.js, Flask, PHP, RESTful APIs

Databases: SQL, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite, Redis

Programming Languages: JavaScript and Python

Development Practices: API Development, Microservices Architecture, Agile Methodologies, TDD Unit

Testing, Integration Testing

Soft Skills: Leadership, Communication, Collaboration, Problem-solving, Time Management

Work Experience

Senior Node.js Developer (Remote) Codeflare LTD, Abuja, Nigeria

- *Aug 2024 Present*
 - Developed high-performance, scalable Node.js applications improving system efficiency by 37%.
 - Implemented **caching strategies** using Redis and **queueing systems** with Bull, reducing **84%** of database queries and improving response time by **55 seconds**.
 - Created and managed CI/CD pipelines using Azure DevOps to automate deployment of APIs to Azure Web App, achieving a 100% bug resolution rate for deployment-related issues.
 - Improved application memory usage by 20% through advanced code refactoring and profiling techniques.

Azure DevOps Engineer (Remote Part-time) xFusionCorp

- *Mar 2021 June 2024*
 - Designed and implemented **customer-driven solutions** on Azure and AWS.
 - Automated CI/CD pipelines using Terraform and Azure DevOps, increasing deployment efficiency by 40%.
 - Managed cloud infrastructure, optimizing **performance and security** for **Azure** and **AWS** environments, reducing operational costs by 20%.
 - Monitored AKS clusters by creating **custom Grafana alerts** for real-time insights and issue detection.
 - Automated deployments using **ArgoCD** for **containerized applications**, cutting deployment time by 50%.

Full-stack Engineer (Onsite Full-Time) Bonjourex

— Jan 2017 – Apr 2024

- Led a team in designing and implementing **Applications** and IT **infrastructure** with **AWS** and **Azure**, resulting in a **30% performance improvement**.
- Develop several API for e-commerce and chat-app with Python, PHP and NodeJS
- Deployed cloud solutions and applied DevOps practices for infrastructure provisioning and application deployment, reducing downtime by 25%.
- Developed high-availability architectures with Terraform on Azure.
- Configured **monitoring systems** using Prometheus and Grafana for tracking performance metrics and system health.

DevOps and Cloud Engineer (Remote Contract)

General Dynamics — Sep 2020 – Sep 2022

- Built and deployed applications on Apache, Nginx, Tomcat, and WebLogic for cloud infrastructure.
- Set up and managed **Kubernetes clusters** using **AWS EKS**, reducing downtime by 15%.
- Automated infrastructure provisioning with Ansible and secured environments using Ansible Vault.
- Managed Azure infrastructure with Terraform and ARM templates, achieving 99.9% uptime.

Cloud and Systems Engineer (Remote Contract)

Biyawa — Sep 2022 – Sep 2023

- Engineered CI/CD pipelines on AWS using ArgoCD and Gitea, increasing deployment speed by 50%.
- Managed system resources like disk and CPU utilization, improving resource efficiency by 25%.
- Implemented AWS IAM policies to ensure secure access control for cloud resources.
- Configured DevOps tools including Jenkins, SonarQube, and Docker, streamlining code quality checks and deployments.

Education

Obafemi Awolowo University, Osun, Nigeria B.Sc.

Biochemistry, Graduated March 2015

Certifications

- Certified DevOps Foundations | LinkedIn Learning, 2024
- Certified SE and DevOps | ALX, 2024
- Certified DevOps Engineer | SkillUp by Simplilearn, 2022
- Python Programming Beginners' Bootcamp | OpenWave, 2022 PHP Test | TestDome, 2022